News and Information Service Records 1947-1994
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections (MASC)
News and Information Service Records
1947-1994
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections (MASC) Holland and Terrell Libraries Pullman, WA 99164-5610 USA (509) 335-6691 http://libraries.wsu.edu/masc/ mascref@wsu.edu
Archives 226
14 linear feet of shelf space 14 containers
Contains information files about individuals who have worked for Washington State University, sports and news releases for each year that extensively cover athletic-oriented activities, workshops, conferences, organizational groups, concert series, committees, speeches, theatrical productions, referendums, initiatives, as well as correspondence files and back-to-school stories.
Organizational History:
The organizational role of the Washington State University News and Information Service, sometime known by its former name of News Bureau, was to provide media agencies with informational stories concerning all aspects of university activities. These activities involve students, faculty, and staff that have contributed newsworthy accomplishments while connected with Washington State University. The activities are divided into general sports and news releases. A number of university-related activities are covered by the WSU News Bureau. These include information files about individuals who have worked for Washington State University, sports and news releases for each year that extensively cover athletic-oriented activities, workshops, conferences, organizational groups, concert series, committees, speeches, theatrical productions, referendums, initiatives, as well as correspondence files and back-to-school stories. Over the years there have been a large number of editors of this organization: Alice Webb (1920s), Herbert Jenkins (1930s), Maynard Hicks (1940s & 1950s), Dennis Morrison (1950s & 1960s), and Richard Fry (1970s & 1980s). Since the 1980s, the director has been Barbara Petura, with Al Ruddy, Sue Hinz and others serving as writers and editors. Other records are located at the WSU Libraries as record group Archives 65, WSU News Bureau releases from 1918 to 1977 and WSU 115, news releases from the early 1920s, located with University Publications. Archives 333 is a subsequent colleciton of WSU News Subject files.
The majority of the materials in this collection are press releases produced by Washington State University, and related documents or articles collected by WSUNews and Information. A relatively small number of photographs can be found in this collection as well, interfiled with the relevant print materials.
The collection is broken into four series of materials. Series 1, the WSU biographical / personnel files, is arranged alphabetically by last name and covers a broad range of years (1940s-1990s). These are effectively vertical files, wherein press releases and other documents relating to individuals have been kept. Series 2 is sports press releases and news releases, are these arranged chronologically and can be accessed by the month and year of their initial release to the public. Each year is represented by a series of folders that denote which month of that year the releases were from. Within each monthly folder, the specific releases for each date are arranged chronologically. In regards to the releases from the 1950's, 1960's, and early 1970's, they are referenced according to whether or not they were miscellaneous or assorted, because there is not a consistent run of dates from those periods. The comprehensive "index to releases" subsection of this series lists, in chronological order, the succession of releases found in the monthly folders. Series 3 is approximately one half a box of departmental correspondence, covering 1969-1979. The fourth and final series of materials are subject files, an assortment of papers and releases in relation to various student and faculty groups at the university as well as information concerning speeches, concerts, plays, committees, workshops, conferences, and institutes that took place at Washington State University. These are arranged alphabetically by topic.
The Collection is open for research use.
Assorted News Bureau Files (ca. 1955- ca. 1995) Records and papers of the Washington State University News and Information Office were transferred to the University Libraries on many occasions. In 1996 much material was drawn together, appraised and arranged, amalgamating documents that had been identified by accession codes UA82-06, 82-10, 85-50, 86-11, 86-22, 87-24, 88-06, 88-16, 88-21, 88-25, 88-33, 89-09, 89-24, 90-28, 91-12, 91-24, 91-28, 92-12, 92-25, 93-10, 94-20, 95-15, 97-01, 97-08, and 98-10.
Washington State University. Office of News and information Services--Archives; State College of Washington. Office of News and Information Services; State College of Washington. News Bureau.; Washington State University. Office of News and Information Services--Records and correspondence; Washington State University. News Bureau--Records and correspondence; Washington State University--History--Archival resources
Universities and colleges--Public relations--Archival resources
Washington (State); Colleges and Universities; Journalism
- Series 1: Biographical and Personnel Files for faculty, staff, and students
  - A - Carter (Box 1)
  - Cass - Gable (Box 2)
  - Gagnon - Holley (Box 3)
  - Holmes - Loposer (Box 4)
  - Lord - Prisk (Box 5)
  - Proctor - Wicklund (Box 6)
- Series 2: News Releases and Sports Releases
  - January 1978 - June 1978 (Box 6)
  - July 1978 - December 1979 (Box 7)
  - January 1980 - September 1981 (Box 8)
  - October 1981 - November 1983 (Box 9)
  - December 1983 - December 1985 (Box 10)
  - January 1986 - December 1986 (Box 11)
  - News Releases, 1956-1980, 1987-1988, undated (Box 11)
  - Index to Releases, 1956-1967 (Box 11)
  - Index to Releases, 1968-1983 (Box 12)
- Series 3: Departmental Correspondence
  - 1969-1979 (Box 12)
- Series 4: Subject Files
  - Agawards, 1950-1959 (Box 12)
  - Agawards, 1961-1970 (Box 12)
  - Alcoa Awards, 1965-1971 (Box 12)
  - Aquatic Art Festival, 1966 (Box 12)
  - ASEE Conference, 1966 (Box 12)
  - Athletic broadcasting rights, 1969 (Box 12)
  - Ashby reception, 1990-1991 (Box 12)
  - Awards, misc, 1962-1982 (Box 12)
  - Back-to-school stories, 1968, 1981-1983, 1988 (Box 12)
  - Bryan Hall concert series, 1983 (Box 13)
  - Campus unrest reports, 1969 (Box 13)
  - Carbon dating conference, 1965 (Box 13)
  - Centennial arch, 1989-1990 (Box 13)
  - Chicano Mobile Institute, 1972 (Box 13)
  - Christmas vespers, 1954-1981 (Box 13)
  - Civil defense, 1955-1980 (Box 13)
  - College Bowl, 1980 (Box 13)
  - The Commedians, 1970-1981 (Box 13)
  - Committees at WSU, 1960-1983 (Box 13)
  - Concerts at WSU, 1974-1983 (Box 13)
  - Crimson and Gray Day, 1991 (Box 13)
  - Engineering awards, 1958-1982 (Box 13)
  - Flood, Pullman, 1972 (Box 13)
  - FFA (Future Farmers of America), 1978-1986 (Box 13)
  - Gala / Showcase on the Arts, 1993 (Box 13)
  - High School Summer Camp, 1961-1985 (Box 13)
  - Hydraulics conference, 1969-1971 (Box 13)
  - Industrial Waste Conference, 1956-1970 (Box 13)
  - Institute for County Commissioners, 1965 (Box 13)
  - Institute in Librarianship, 1965-1970 (Box 13)
  - Institute of Technology, 1950-1965 (Box 13)
  - JESSI (Junior Engineers and Scientists Summer Institute), 1960-1965 (Box 13)
  - Job Fair, 1977 (Box 13)
  - Library dedication: Holland Addition, 1994 (Box 13)
  - Lifetime Sports Clinic, 1968 (Box 13)
  - Light Metals Utilization and Fabrication Conference, 1955 (Box 13)
  - Mademoiselle magazine board, 1947-1954 (Box 13)
  - McEachern-Boesendorfer series, 1982-1983 (Box 13)
  - Musica Viva, 1977-1979 (Box 13)
  - National Defense Graduate Fellowship, 1961-1962 (Box 13)
  - National Science Foundation, 1968-1979 (Box 13)
  - National Shakespeare Company, 1974-1976 (Box 13)
  - NDEA Counseling & Guidance Institute, 1962-1968 (Box 13)
  - NDEA Institute in Speech, 1967-1968 (Box 13)
  - Northwestern Conference on Diseases in Nature Communicable to Man, 1970 (Box 13)
  - PNW Conference on Higher Education, 1957-1958 (Box 13)
  - PNW Plastic Conference, 1970-1972 (Box 13)
  - Palouse Empire Concert Series, 1967-1980 (Box 13)
  - Peace Corps, 1962-1981 (Box 13)
  - Philadelphia String Quartet, 1966-1983 (Box 13)
  - Poultry Science Association, 1975 (Box 13)
  - Pullman Community Theatre, 1969-1972 (Box 14)
  - Question Center, 1977-1979 (Box 14)
  - Racism Workshops, 1970-1971 (Box 14)
  - Referendums & Initiatives, 1950-1966 (Box 14)
  - Regents Meetings, 1963-1982 (Box 14)
  - Renaissance Conference, 1967 (Box 14)
  - The Ritz (WSU Choral Company), 1979-1983 (Box 14)
  - Scholars Convocation, 1962-1970 (Box 14)
  - Speakers & Speeches, 1966-1979 (Box 14)
  - Student Strike, 1970 (Box 14)
  - Thermal Power Conference, 1970-1978 (Box 14)
  - Transit system and Van pools, 1973-1985 (Box 14)
  - Turnkey Apartments, 1975-1977 (Box 14)
  - University Black Theatre Ensemble, 1975-1976 (Box 14)
  - USDA Wenatchee facility, 1976 (Box 14)
  - Vet Med photos, undated (Box 14)
  - Washington Association of Civil Defense Directors, 1971 (Box 14)
  - Washington State Grange Convention, 1960-1969 (Box 14)
  - Webster Hall dedication, 1994 (Box 14)
  - Well Drillers' Association, 1966-1971 (Box 14)
  - Woodrow Wilson Fellowships, 1961-1971 (Box 14)
  - World Affairs Institute, 1965-1971 (Box 14)